<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>YeungYeah's Blog</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/</link><description>Record the YeungYeah's thoughts and actions.</description><generator>Hugo 0.122.0 https://gohugo.io/</generator><language>en-US</language><managingEditor>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</managingEditor><webMaster>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:52:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://scottyeung.top/en/atom.xml"/><item><title>Translating Blog Posts with Claude Skills</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/claude-skills-to-translate/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/claude-skills-to-translate/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:28:54 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>I previously set up an &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/en/">English version&lt;/a> of my blog (the process is documented in &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/2024/setup-english-blog/">Setting Up My English Blog with Hugo&lt;/a>), where I publish some articles translated into English using AI. The original workflow was: after writing an article, I would paste it into a large language model's chat window, use a fixed prompt to translate it into English while maintaining the same markdown format, then copy the output and create a new file in the corresponding directory for English content. This involved copying and pasting several times and manually creating new files each time. It was fairly quick, but after getting familiar with Claude Code, I wondered if I could make it even more convenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I decided to use &lt;a href="https://code.claude.com/docs/en/skills#create-your-first-skill">Claude Skills&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is a Claude Skill?
Skills are modular, self-contained extension packages that expand Claude's capabilities by providing specialized knowledge, workflows, and tools. Think of them as &amp;quot;onboarding guides&amp;quot; for specific domains or tasks—they transform Claude from a general-purpose agent into a specialized agent equipped with procedural knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>By defining a SKILL.md document, you can create a skill that describes the execution steps and instructions, along with external executable code and reference materials. With a single command, you can have Claude Code perform the corresponding operations. Taking blog translation as an example, I created a SKILL.md file in the &lt;code>./claude/skills/translate-post&lt;/code> directory of my project with the following content:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt"> 1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 4
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 5
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 6
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 7
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 8
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 9
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">10
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">11
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-md" data-lang="md">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">---
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">name: translate-post
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">description: transalte post&amp;#39;s content from Chinese into English
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">disable-model-invocation: true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">---
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">transalte the specific post file $ARGUMENTS content into English
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">1.&lt;/span> read file $ARGUMENTS all text content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">2.&lt;/span> translate all content into English. cannot drop any content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">3.&lt;/span> create a text file in content_en directory but with the same path with original file in content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>Very simple instructions: read the file content, translate it into English, and create a file in the specified directory. Here, $ARGUMENTS is the input parameter. When actually running it, you just need to enter the command &lt;code>/translate-post @content/posts/2026/post.md&lt;/code>, and Claude Code will automatically create a file with the same name under &lt;code>content_en/posts/2026/&lt;/code>, with the translated content inside.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Blog/">Blog</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Automation/">Automation</category></item><item><title>Truly Embracing AI</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/embrace-ai-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/embrace-ai-again/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:50:08 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>Claude Code has been around and popular for a while now. When it first came out, I actually tried it using the API mode, but at that time I found it rather clumsy. Back then, CC got stuck on common network issues while installing dependencies, and the process was interrupted at the very first step. Plus, the token consumption was too intense to afford on my own, so I didn't pay much attention to it afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, my company has started promoting Claude Code internally, providing a free monthly token quota and corresponding internal API access. We can now use Claude Code at work, and some team members have been sharing their experiences with it. So this week I tried using Claude Code at work, but the internal rate limiting was too aggressive. I could feel its power, but the user experience was just average.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So these past two days I started using Claude Code on my personal projects. At first, I was thinking about whether I could use it for free, learning from the company's approach by finding some free tokens and then using Claude Code through the API. Both Doubao and Qianwen work for this - basically every provider now gives some token quota when you create a new account and generate an API Key. Doubao gives 500K, and then you can get several million tokens by completing some tasks. Qianwen gives 1 million tokens. The experience is actually quite decent, but the token consumption is still pretty fast. After two days with Doubao, I had already used about 6 million tokens, and continuing would require payment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I'd have to pay anyway, I might as well go all in and try the genuine, native Claude Code. I had just switched to a better VPN service with good US nodes, so using it shouldn't be a problem. So I looked for ways to subscribe. Unfortunately, Anthropic doesn't support domestic credit cards for payment - you can only pay through third-party virtual cards or gift cards. I ended up choosing services from &lt;a href="https://meiguo.app/">Meiguo&lt;/a>. Initially, I knew they offered credit card services, but later I found out they also provide gift card services directly. Claude Code Pro only requires a +$4 service fee and supports WeChat payment, which is very convenient. I got one, received the gift card via email, and used it to activate the membership myself. If you're interested, give it a try using my &lt;a href="https://meiguo.app?ref=O63O3">referral code O63O3&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After switching to the genuine native Claude Code, the experience went up another level. The official version feels like a smarter model with stronger development capabilities, and the development ideas and plans it outputs are clearer and more precise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've actually been in contact with AI and large language models for quite some time. When ChatGPT first came out, I was already using it - you could say I've been keeping up with the latest developments all along. But I feel like I've always just been scratching the surface. For new things, I try them once, think they're amazing, marvel at them for a moment, or find them not useful and complain a bit, and then that's it. Even the amazing and useful ones, I don't continue using them or integrate them into my work and life. The not-so-useful ones, I don't think about how to make them useful or how to actually use them. I vaguely sense that I might be gradually falling behind in this era of intelligence. Especially when I see more and more people around me starting to do vibe coding, or using AI and large language models for various things, I start comparing and getting anxious. I really need to use it more, use it in all kinds of ways, use it in daily life, use it at work, and integrate it into life.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Coding/">Coding</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Software/">Software</category></item><item><title>Investing with Alpha Picks</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/use-alpha-picks-invest/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/use-alpha-picks-invest/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:51:10 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>My previous individual stock investments have always lacked a proper methodology. In the middle of last year, I studied some concepts of value investing and learned about company valuation analysis and stock selection methods, but with limited energy and time, and perhaps limited skill level, I ultimately didn't spend much time carefully researching individual stocks. It then evolved into watching YouTube or other platforms - whoever mentioned a certain stock, I'd take a look and buy it based on feeling. When to buy, how much to buy, when to add to positions, when to sell - all based on feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized I needed to create my own trading system. No matter how good or bad, it's better than doing things randomly. The domestic fund DCA investments have basically formed a fixed plan and don't need much attention anymore. For US stocks, during last year's Black Friday, I purchased a Seeking Alpha premium membership and their Alpha Picks service. This post is a record of my attempts to explore and use Alpha Picks for investing during this period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-alpha-picks">What is Alpha Picks?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Alpha Picks is a paid stock-picking service launched by Seeking Alpha. Based on collected data, it uses quantitative methods to select two stocks per month for users. The stocks it has selected have achieved returns of 270+% to date, which is more than 3 times the S&amp;amp;P 500 index.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260109231402620.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The official portfolio operation logic is: at the beginning and middle of each month, a new STRONG BUY stock is added with a fixed position size purchased. Then when the stock's quantitative rating drops to below SELL, or drops to HOLD for 180 days, it will be sold.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-should-new-users-use-it">How Should New Users Use It?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When new users now activate Alpha Picks, there are already dozens of stocks in the portfolio. The official recommendation is to pick 5 STRONG BUY stocks to purchase, or directly buy the entire portfolio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through communication with Gemini, Gemini provided an operation guide for reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fZ_0du3qfKGU_5BtFEgDxOBwa5TEQMjC5yLwj_wXsc0/edit?usp=sharing">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fZ_0du3qfKGU_5BtFEgDxOBwa5TEQMjC5yLwj_wXsc0/edit?usp=sharing&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>As an ordinary investor, if you want to make money by following Alpha Picks, &lt;strong>you shouldn't pursue 100% perfect mechanical replication, but rather grasp its core logic and adopt a simplified execution plan&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a best practices guide for ordinary investors:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-core-mindset-execute-like-a-machine-trust-the-system">1. Core Mindset: Execute Like a Machine (Trust the System)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is the hardest part. Alpha Picks is based on quantitative data (Quant Ratings), and its stock selection logic is often counterintuitive.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Situations you may encounter:&lt;/strong> It recommends an obscure stock you've never heard of, or a stock that you think has already risen too much, or even from an industry you personally dislike (such as coal, or even certain consumer stocks).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What to do:&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Pinch your nose and buy.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong> If you've subscribed to this service, trust its algorithm. The biggest source of losses for ordinary investors often comes from &amp;quot;I feel this stock isn't good&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;This stock has risen too high, I dare not buy.&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="2-position-building-phase-how-to-start-getting-started">2. Position Building Phase: How to Start? (Getting Started)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you just subscribed today, facing 30+ historical holdings, how do you buy?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Official/Ideal advice:&lt;/strong> Buy the entire portfolio according to current weights.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ordinary person/Realistic advice:&lt;/strong> With limited funds, don't buy all 30.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Strategy:&lt;/strong> Only buy the top 5-10 stocks currently rated &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Strong Buy&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reason:&lt;/strong> Although those early &amp;quot;winners&amp;quot; have risen a lot, if their current rating has dropped to &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot;, there's no need to chase highs to build positions now. Only buy those with the strongest current data.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="3-daily-operations-twice-monthly-new-stock-day-the-monthly-routine">3. Daily Operations: Twice-Monthly &amp;quot;New Stock Day&amp;quot; (The Monthly Routine)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Alpha Picks usually has two new recommendations (Picks) per month.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Capital allocation:&lt;/strong> Try to ensure that the amount invested each time is roughly the same (Equal Weighting).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Wrong approach:&lt;/em> This month I have money, buy $2000; next month I don't have money, only buy $200. This will cause your performance to be dominated by the stock with the large position.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Correct approach:&lt;/em> Set a fixed &amp;quot;monthly contribution&amp;quot; amount. For example, DCA $1000 per month, $500 for each new stock. If there's surplus, save it for the next time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="4-selling-rules-strictly-follow-discipline-selling-rules">4. Selling Rules: Strictly Follow Discipline (Selling Rules)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is the key to Alpha Picks outperforming the market — &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Let profits run, cut losses short.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When to sell?&lt;/strong> Only sell when you receive an official email notification. There are usually two situations:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rating plunge:&lt;/strong> The stock rating directly drops to &lt;strong>Sell&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Strong Sell&lt;/strong> — &lt;strong>Sell immediately&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rating stagnation:&lt;/strong> The stock rating drops to &lt;strong>Hold&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>remains at Hold for 180 consecutive days&lt;/strong> — &lt;strong>Sell&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note:&lt;/em> Many ordinary investors panic and want to sell when they see it become &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot; - this is wrong. Alpha Picks allows stocks to adjust in &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot; status for half a year, which often captures subsequent gains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sell regardless of profit or loss:&lt;/strong> Even if you've lost 40% on this stock, if the system says sell, you must sell (stop loss); even if you've made 200% on this stock, if the system hasn't said sell, don't sell just to &amp;quot;lock in gains&amp;quot; (not only to let profits run, but also to avoid missing the main upward wave).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="5-capital-reinvestment-simplify-your-life-simplifying-reinvestment">5. Capital Reinvestment: Simplify Your Life (Simplifying Reinvestment)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Back to the capital handling issue you're most concerned about.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Don't:&lt;/strong> Every time you sell a stock, take out your calculator and split a few hundred dollars evenly among the remaining 20 stocks. This will create a lot of fractional shares and tax headaches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Do:&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Capital pool&amp;quot; strategy&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you sell a stock (say you recoup $1000), or receive a dividend (say $50), treat all this money as &lt;strong>&amp;quot;ammunition for the next purchase&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Directly invest this money into the &lt;strong>next recommended new stock&lt;/strong>, or add to the current &lt;strong>top 3 Strong Buy&lt;/strong> stocks.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="summary-the-lazy-protocol-for-ordinary-investors">Summary: The &amp;quot;Lazy Protocol&amp;quot; for Ordinary Investors&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Operation Step&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Official Complex Instructions&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Recommended Approach for Ordinary People&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>What to buy&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Configure entire portfolio by weight&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Only buy &lt;strong>latest recommendations&lt;/strong> + current highest-rated &lt;strong>Strong Buys&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>How much to buy&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Strictly equal split&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Try to use &lt;strong>fixed amounts&lt;/strong> (e.g., $500 per stock), no need to be too precise&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Sale proceeds&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Split evenly among all remaining holdings&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Save it&lt;/strong>, buy the next two newly recommended stocks in full&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Dividends&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Split evenly among all remaining holdings&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Save it&lt;/strong>, accumulate enough to buy new stocks, or enable automatic reinvestment (DRIP)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Mindset&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rational quantitative&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Even if the stock is ugly or you don't know it, &lt;strong>buy with eyes closed&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Following this simplified strategy, you can capture 95%+ of Alpha Picks' returns, but reduce operational complexity by 90%.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Investment/">Investment</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Notes/">Notes</category></item><item><title>2025 Annual Record</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/record-of-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/record-of-2025/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>As per my annual tradition, I'm reviewing 2025 through a journal-style account and recording some thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/Gemini_Generated_Image_6z6pef6z6pef6z6p.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timeline">Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="january">January&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The BU and team started mass recruiting contractors to become the main force for project implementation going forward. Full-time employees needed to become so-called &amp;quot;architects&amp;quot; leading the contractors. Setting aside whether I, someone who had only been with the company for a year and a half, was qualified to be a so-called architect - in upper management's view, throwing more people at problems solves everything. Full-time employees too expensive? Then pile on contractors. Can the contractors handle it? Even if they can't, someone has to lead them. Even if efficiency is low, as long as the base number is large, it's still better than zero. So the boss started leading a contractor team, which gradually expanded to several times the size of the full-time employee count. Later, each full-time employee led several contractors, ultimately becoming a &amp;quot;labor contractor.&amp;quot; For someone like me who had only been out of campus recruitment for two years, is being a labor contractor really a good thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, taking advantage of this contractor recruitment opportunity, I went to Changsha twice in January for communication and guidance with them. Changsha is a nice place. Although I didn't get to go anywhere fun during the business trip, the food was decent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I went home for Spring Festival, the family's new house was ready to move into. We moved to another residential complex with a better environment, bigger rooms, and easier parking spaces - very comfortable. Especially after the parking upgrade, I no longer need to ask my father for help parking the car when I drive back.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="march">March&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On the first day of March, while playing in Hong Kong, I suddenly saw news that Khalil Fong had passed away. Several people messaged me about it. As a long-time fan of Khalil Fong, my first reaction was bewilderment and disbelief - he had just made a comeback last year, released a new album, and appeared on shows, and suddenly I see such terrible news. Besides feeling sad for him, I increasingly felt that life is impermanent. Nothing truly lasts forever; people really can die suddenly, regardless of age or status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the month, after performance reviews came out, I got my first good rating and promotion. However, looking at that bit of year-end bonus and salary increase, I felt it was just so-so. Even though this was called the best year, the money wasn't that much - especially comparing the year-end bonus between good and average performance ratings, the extra two months wasn't that much more money. I don't know what the point is (though maybe it's because my base salary isn't high enough). Also, I've always found it rather absurd that promotion is tied to performance. Promotion should mean your abilities have reached the next level, so promotion makes your level match your ability. However, performance only reflects the year's work - whether you met or exceeded expectations. The two aren't really related. I've even often seen lower-level employees assigned higher-level work and used as higher-level employees, but when it comes to performance reviews, because they're doing higher-level work, their targets and expectations are higher, resulting in not getting good performance ratings and naturally no promotion. It all depends on the boss's conscience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="april---june">April - June&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During Labor Day holiday, my girlfriend and I went to Kunming. It was my first time back in Yunnan since graduating from elementary school. Kunming's weather is really comfortable, and Yunnan cuisine and mushrooms are delicious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June, the team outing was to Chongzuo, Guangxi again. Originally we considered keeping it relaxed and not too intense, but in the end it felt too relaxed - we didn't really go anywhere fun, and ultimately just played cards heavily with colleagues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going out to play was quite fun, although work was still there. Unfortunately, I still couldn't completely disconnect during holidays. Before, it was more about not daring to, afraid of being escalated. Now it's become more about worrying that things might go wrong or progress might stall, so I proactively check even during holidays.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="august---november">August - November&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The company planned to focus heavily on the Brazilian market, and the big boss suddenly thought about sending us tech people to Brazil for local support. Honestly, I don't understand what a tech person can accomplish by going to Brazil for a two-month business trip, but it was the boss's idea, and we could only comply. Initially, the manager collected everyone's preferences to see if anyone would volunteer. But obviously no one did - the time difference, security issues, language barrier, and long distance were all very discouraging factors. Eventually it became a rotation within the team - the manager went first, I was in the second batch, and even +2 couldn't avoid it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101200933342.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After it was confirmed I was going, it was all kinds of preparations - applying for visa, booking flights, reserving hotels. During this process, I kept receiving all sorts of negative information about Brazil from social media and colleagues already stationed there - like poor security, poor infrastructure. The main concern was the security issue, with various thefts and robberies. I even saw a post during National Day about a Huawei employee being shot and their laptop stopping the bullet and saving their life. Really scary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this mindset, I departed for Brazil with another colleague after National Day, flying over twenty hours total before landing in São Paulo. Then, being overly cautious - maybe I was dizzy from the flight - when I took an Uber from the airport to the hotel, I left my backpack in the car. It wasn't until over two hours later, after checking in and eating, that I realized I had left my backpack in the car - with my two laptops and an iPad inside. Although I immediately tried to contact the Uber driver, Uber's lost and found mechanism is absolutely ridiculous. You can't get the driver's contact information to reach them directly; you can only wait for the platform to forward your message to the driver, then have the driver reply to the platform to forward back to you. With all this back and forth, the driver didn't reply until the next morning. Plus, electronic products are really expensive locally in Brazil, so I never got it back. Filing a police report only got me a report receipt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So my Brazil business trip started catastrophically - I lost all electronic devices except my phone right after landing, including my work computer and personal computer (two MacBook Pros). Losing the devices, my first reaction was actually heartache over the money, but my immediate thought was: my computer is gone, how am I supposed to work?? I had already accumulated two days of work matters during the flight, and now my computer was gone. Fortunately, I managed to get help from local IT and borrowed a computer. The tough part was that the loaner was only a Windows laptop - an old 2019 Dell notebook - but I had to make do. In the end, I got through it. Despite the time difference and crappy equipment, there were no major problems with work, I adapted well to life there, and I didn't encounter any security issues afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting aside the accident and work, the Brazil business trip was actually quite interesting. Although security wasn't great, as long as you don't go out at night, only take taxis when going out, and don't look at your phone outside, you basically don't encounter major problems. In distant São Paulo, I experienced quite a few new things and ate a lot of food - even ate quite authentic Chinese food. One Sichuan restaurant could even rival many restaurants back in China. Also, the two-month business trip incidentally earned me Marriott Platinum and Hilton Diamond status, and I started consciously building up hotel memberships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this Brazil trip, I became even more aware that my English really isn't good enough, especially in speaking. Communicating with local colleagues was rather strained and difficult. I've been learning English all along, but I've never reached a level that satisfies me, which is really a pity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="december">December&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After returning from Brazil, since all my devices were lost, I had to buy new ones. I was previously all-in on the Apple ecosystem and had been wanting to leave it, but if I bought another MacBook Pro + iPad, I'd be spending another 20k RMB, which I couldn't bear. So I switched to an Android tablet + Windows laptop and gradually adapted. I also gradually realized that these are just tools - basically anything can achieve the goal and meet requirements, it's just a matter of how smooth it feels. Of course, switching ecosystems was also because I wanted to experience something new.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thoughts">Thoughts&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="work--life">Work &amp;amp; Life&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As work becomes increasingly busy and high-pressure, work's proportion in life and its invasion into life has also increased. For example, in this year's annual review, most of it is actually work or work-related matters. There aren't many personal or life matters, and even the second half of the year was mainly due to the Brazil business trip. It's rather sad - work is gradually alienating me. The few days before New Year's, I actually took three days off to piece together an eight-day mini vacation, but I couldn't stop worrying about various projects. Even after turning off notifications, I still worried about work issues or if someone was looking for me, so I'd occasionally check in and reply to messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work is becoming less and less interesting, not just because of the complaints mentioned above. During work, I increasingly feel the &amp;quot;cog in the machine&amp;quot; nature of technology. Business is the core; BD is way more important than tech. No matter how fancy the tech is, it's useless without business - no one will use it. For example, in the payment acquiring field, no matter how many features you provide, it's not as good as lowering the fees a bit more. Technology becomes &amp;quot;basic&amp;quot; at this point, and basic things naturally have difficulty arguing for value since everyone has them. Maybe all jobs at big companies are like this. I hope to experience a different work environment. If there are good job opportunities, feel free to contact me 🤣&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="money--investment">Money &amp;amp; Investment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Work is boring; making money is the core. After opening a US stock account last year, riding the overall upward trend, I made a little profit in stocks. This year I also increased my principal investment and am accumulating and investing through different strategies across various accounts. However, in stock trading, I still haven't formed a trading system. Maybe I watched a few videos with analysis saying a certain stock is undervalued and bought in, then kept adding to the position as it went lower, and ended up deeply trapped. Investing is really a very professional matter that requires continuous time investment to learn. But under the current high-intensity work situation, the time and energy I invest in US stocks is actually decreasing. Maybe the ultimate destination is still the path of accumulating money through index funds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides individual US stocks, this year I've been continuously adjusting my DCA approach for index ETFs. Initially, I just randomly DCA'd into NASDAQ and S&amp;amp;P 500 on Alipay. After opening the US stock account, I also bought some on-exchange ETFs there. But later I realized that for DCA into indices, domestic QDII funds would suffice, so there's no need to do it in the US stock account. Then in the second half of the year, NASDAQ suddenly became hot in the public eye again, and everyone started DCA into NASDAQ. Off-exchange funds started limiting quotas one after another - limits of fifty or a hundred, even some limiting to 10 yuan per day, which is ridiculous. Then some simply stopped accepting subscriptions, so these past two months I've shifted to on-exchange funds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101211346636.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking back at the overall returns: Alipay funds made 9 percentage points, US stocks are still down 2 percentage points. Either way, both underperformed the broader market. Need to work harder and adjust more carefully next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this process, I started regularly recording all assets this year - how much is in each account, how much in total. I set up a Google Sheet and record it once a month. Through this numerical recording method, I can very clearly see the changes in my savings. Saving money really isn't easy - maybe I'm just not earning enough. I'm still working toward saving my first million RMB, hoping to achieve it early this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The more I write, the more I feel like work has brought me too much negative energy, haha. The annual review and summary seems to have turned into a complaint session. Complaining is useless; I still need to do something to make a change. I've been reading &lt;a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/32567134/">&lt;em>The Compound Effect&lt;/em>&lt;/a> recently, which mentions that even doing small things, as long as you persist, will eventually be effective. In the new year, whether it's saving money, learning English, or life in general, I hope to do a little bit more every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101211407117.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Record/">Record</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Summary/">Summary</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Life/">Life</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Investment/">Investment</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Work/">Work</category></item><item><title>Scoop Install Specific Version App</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/scoop-install-specific-version-app/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/scoop-install-specific-version-app/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:36:07 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>After switching to the Windows environment and re-setting up some software, when pulling back my blog and setting up hugo, I encountered &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/2025/degrade-homebrew-app-version/">the same issue as before where the hugo version was too high and incompatible with my local blog theme&lt;/a>, requiring me to downgrade hugo to a specific version. In the macOS environment, applications are managed through Homebrew; in Windows, this is done through Scoop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I asked Gemini, and the response was that Scoop, like Homebrew, doesn't support installing specific versions of applications, but you can install older versions by specifying a URL to a specific manifest file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So you just need to go to Scoop's software repository, find the manifest file for the corresponding application, view the commit history, and find the source file URL for the historical version.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to Scoop's GitHub repository (usually &lt;a href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/tree/master/bucket">ScoopMain&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/tree/master/bucket">ScoopExtras&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the &lt;code>.json&lt;/code> file for the corresponding software (e.g., &lt;code>nodejs.json&lt;/code>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>History&lt;/strong> in the upper right corner to view commit history.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the commit record for the version you want and click to view the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Raw&lt;/strong> button and copy the URL from the browser address bar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>The URL looks like this:&lt;/em> &lt;code>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/.../commit_hash/.../app.json&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then install using this URL. Installing by specifying the manifest URL this way means the installed app cannot be updated - the version is automatically locked.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop install https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/4e72c5167244e249bbb063a93c28bb8aac034682/bucket/hugo-extended.json
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>However, finding historical versions of manifest files this way is actually very troublesome - you need to flip through page by page, and if the version is older, you'll have to flip for quite a while. After searching, I found that Scoop actually does support downloading specific versions of applications. After downloading a specific version, you can use the hold command to prevent updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">4
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="c1"># Install specific version&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop install &amp;lt;app&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="c1"># The scoop hold command prevents apps from being updated.&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop hold &amp;lt;apps&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>Actually, this command can be seen in Scoop's help command. Gemini was a bit unreliable - even after I discovered that downloading specific versions was possible, it still stubbornly refused to admit it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/%7B0C842582-CFE1-488E-A12E-C0A4F71AA517%7D.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Windows/">Windows</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Experience/">Experience</category></item><item><title>Logseq Remove Blank Journal Pages</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-remove-blank-journals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-remove-blank-journals/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 12:38:08 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>When Logseq opens, it automatically creates a Journal page for the current day. Normally, when opening Logseq, you probably do want to make a record most of the time, so this feature seems fine. However, if Logseq isn't completely exited after opening, it will still create Journal pages every day as usual. Over time, when you open Logseq, you'll see a bunch of blank pages, which is very annoying, and it also makes browsing previous Journal entries very inconvenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To avoid this situation, I used to remind myself to press Command + Q to completely exit Logseq after using it, and for the occasional times I forgot, I would manually delete the blank pages. But in reality, it's very easy to forget to exit, and then maybe because of work, I wouldn't open it again for a week, accumulating a bunch of blank pages at once. Manually deleting them one by one is also quite tedious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, I thought about simply writing a script to scan for blank markdown files in the directory, but when I opened the local directory, I found that blank Journal pages don't necessarily create blank files. Later, I searched online and discovered that there's actually a built-in removal function for this, and the removal scope isn't limited to just blank Journals - all blank Pages can be scanned and removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specific path to the feature: All pages -&amp;gt; ... -&amp;gt; Remove orphaned pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202508311310890.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202508311310930.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Software/">Software</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Logseq/">Logseq</category></item><item><title>How to Sync Logseq</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-sync/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-sync/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 22:30:09 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>Logseq is a bi-directional note-taking software similar to Obsidian. I've been using it sporadically for several years, but syncing/backup can be quite troublesome, especially across multiple devices of different system types. Both Logseq and Obsidian operate by loading a local folder as the note repository, so syncing notes essentially means syncing this folder. However, achieving a seamless experience across different systems and devices can be a bit of a hassle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s a summary of the various stages I’ve gone through, trying different methods at each stage, none of which worked perfectly. In the end, I opted for the official sync feature, which costs $5 per month.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="syncing-between-pcs-using-onedrive">Syncing Between PCs Using OneDrive&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I first started using Logseq, I only used it on my computer and didn’t even think about checking or taking notes on my phone. At that time, I only needed to sync notes between two PCs. This was relatively simple—just choose a cloud storage service that supports real-time folder syncing, such as OneDrive or Nutstore. I used OneDrive back then, and the syncing was smooth. Since I rarely edited notes on both devices simultaneously, I didn’t encounter major issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="syncing-using-icloud">Syncing Using iCloud&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Later, I switched to an iPhone and needed to sync notes between my iPhone and PC. Naturally, I considered using iCloud for syncing, as iCloud can also be installed on Windows for syncing. Initially, I used iCloud to sync between my iPhone and Windows PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, iCloud syncing often caused issues, especially on Windows devices. Sometimes, files would have multiple versions due to sync problems during normal use. Occasionally, a file version would fail to download for unknown reasons. When this happened, Logseq would get stuck trying to download the file, freezing the interface and crashing the program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To resolve this, I had to manually locate and delete the problematic files in the iCloud storage directory. Obsidian also faces similar issues, but these freezes only occur when opening the software, not during use. Additionally, identifying and deleting duplicate files in the iCloud directory is nearly impossible on mobile devices. If this issue arises while using the app on a phone, it’s essentially unresolvable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After switching my PC to a Mac, these sync conflicts and multi-version issues largely disappeared. However, I encountered another issue during actual use: file syncing and retrieval could be delayed. For example, if I wrote a journal entry on the computer today, the phone might not detect the update before opening the app. When the app opens, it might create a new note for today, overwriting the computer's entry. Fortunately, Logseq has a &lt;code>bak&lt;/code> folder for backups, so the data can be recovered, but it requires manual intervention outside the program.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="git-syncing">Git Syncing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before switching to a Mac, I tried another approach using Git to sync notes due to iCloud’s issues on Windows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Logseq has built-in Git version control capabilities, automatically committing changes at regular intervals (e.g., every minute). On the PC, you can configure Git hooks to automatically push commits to a remote repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On iOS, I used a-shell and Shortcuts to pull and sync files. Specifically, I used Shortcuts to pull changes when opening Logseq and to commit and push changes when closing the app.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This method allowed syncing notes across devices, but simultaneous edits could still cause issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although the workflow seemed feasible, the actual experience was subpar due to various issues:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>My remote repository was on GitHub, and pulling changes on mobile often failed due to network issues, preventing the mobile app from syncing to the latest version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conflicts could arise, requiring manual resolution using Git, which necessitated user intervention.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="syncing-between-android-and-pc-using-google-drive">Syncing Between Android and PC Using Google Drive&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I switched back to an Android phone, iCloud was no longer an option, so I turned to Google Drive. That’s when I realized that most cloud storage services on Android don’t offer native two-way folder syncing like iCloud. To achieve this, I had to use third-party apps (e.g., AutoSync). However, these services had significant drawbacks. First, they required granting full read/write permissions for cloud storage, raising security concerns. Additionally, syncing was slow and prone to failure, as it relied on periodic syncing tasks to fetch the latest files from Drive. After a few attempts, I uninstalled the app and revoked its permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="official-sync-feature">Official Sync Feature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All the aforementioned methods essentially rely on external systems or software to sync the contents of the note folder. This inevitably creates a problem: Logseq itself is unaware of the syncing process or whether the files have been fully synced. Each time the app is opened, it assumes the files are already synced and processes them accordingly. This can lead to simultaneous read/write operations between Logseq and the external system, causing issues. This is the root cause of many of the sync problems mentioned above.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Side note: Obsidian has many internal plugins for syncing. Could Logseq provide a similar plugin-based syncing solution? Why are there so few sync-related plugins for Logseq? Perhaps the developers haven’t opened up the necessary APIs for such capabilities?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>After struggling with syncing on Android, I finally decided to pay for the official sync feature. Logseq now offers a sync service that, although still in beta, works seamlessly across devices (Android, Mac, iPad). For just $5 per month, you can enable it. Detailed setup instructions are available in the &lt;a href="https://blog.logseq.com/how-to-setup-and-use-logseq-sync/">official documentation&lt;/a>. Payment options include credit cards (Visa/Master), Google Pay, or PayPal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The official sync feature supports syncing up to 10 graphs. On forums like v2ex, some users share their sync slots to save money. While each graph is encrypted with a separate password, sharing slots poses security risks. For instance, creating a graph for someone else requires sharing your account credentials. Additionally, it seems that removing a remote graph doesn’t require a password, potentially allowing malicious deletion of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Sync Method&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Advantages&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Disadvantages&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>OneDrive Sync&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>PC-to-PC Sync&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Smooth syncing&lt;br>• Easy to set up&lt;br>• Minimal conflict issues&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Limited to PC devices&lt;br>• Limited support for mobile devices&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>iCloud Sync&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>iPhone + PC/Mac&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Relatively stable in Mac environments&lt;br>• Native iOS support&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Prone to file conflicts on Windows&lt;br>• Sync delays may cause data overwrites&lt;br>• Difficult to resolve conflicts on mobile&lt;br>• App may freeze&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Git Sync&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Cross-Platform Users&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Strong version control&lt;br>• Supports auto-commits&lt;br>• Theoretically supports all platforms&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Sync failures due to network issues&lt;br>• Requires manual conflict resolution&lt;br>• Complex setup&lt;br>• Difficult for mobile use&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Google Drive + Third-Party Sync&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Android + PC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Supports Android platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Requires third-party app permissions&lt;br>• High security risks&lt;br>• Slow and unreliable syncing&lt;br>• Only periodic syncing&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Official Sync Feature&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All Devices&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Built-in, seamless experience&lt;br>• Supports multiple devices (Android, Mac, iPad)&lt;br>• Encrypted and secure&lt;br>• Syncs up to 10 graphs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>• Requires payment ($5/month)&lt;br>• Still in beta&lt;br>• Slot-sharing poses security risks&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For PC-only use&lt;/strong>: Cloud storage services like OneDrive are sufficient.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For Mac + iOS environments&lt;/strong>: iCloud is generally usable but watch out for sync delays.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For cross-platform use involving Android&lt;/strong>: The official sync feature is the best choice. Although it requires payment, it offers the best experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For tech-savvy users&lt;/strong>: Git syncing is an option but requires expertise in conflict resolution.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Software/">Software</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Productivity/">Productivity</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Notes/">Notes</category></item><item><title>Downgrade to a Specific Version of an Application in Homebrew</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/degrade-homebrew-app-version/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/degrade-homebrew-app-version/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:21:17 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>I always have the habit of updating all software to the latest version. However, while writing a blog, I discovered that after updating Hugo, there were issues running it locally.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code class="language-log" data-lang="log">ERROR deprecated: site config key paginate was deprecated in Hugo v0.128.0 and subsequently removed. Use pagination.pagerSize instead.
ERROR deprecated: resources.ToCSS was deprecated in Hugo v0.128.0 and subsequently removed. Use css.Sass instead.
ERROR deprecated: .Site.IsMultiLingual was deprecated in Hugo v0.124.0 and subsequently removed. Use hugo.IsMultilingual instead.
ERROR deprecated: .Site.Author was deprecated in Hugo v0.124.0 and subsequently removed. Implement taxonomy &amp;#39;author&amp;#39; or use .Site.Params.Author instead.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>From the error messages, it’s clear that Hugo introduced breaking changes in the update. After the upgrade, some fields and methods were directly removed. At first glance, the error messages seemed helpful, offering alternative fields. However, after making those replacements, I realized it wasn’t as simple as it seemed. The site wouldn’t run. So, I had to downgrade Hugo to its previous version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the steps I followed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Run &lt;code>brew info hugo&lt;/code> to find the repository and path of the application you want to downgrade.
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202503151706238.png" alt="">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In my case, I used a mirror. The original repo is hosted on GitHub.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to the corresponding repository on GitHub and locate the relevant file.
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The file path can be referenced here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/blob/master/Formula/h/hugo.rb">https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/blob/master/Formula/h/hugo.rb&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the commit history of this file and find the commit ID of the version you want to downgrade to.
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Based on the commit ID, you can identify the version, which is usually submitted by the bot &lt;code>BrewTestBot&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you have the commit ID, you can retrieve the URL of the formula file and its content.
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Example: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/blob/2fd8dba871a6a5412fa7c00b12ac99b5738cd199/Formula/h/hugo.rb">https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/blob/2fd8dba871a6a5412fa7c00b12ac99b5738cd199/Formula/h/hugo.rb&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Raw content: &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/2fd8dba871a6a5412fa7c00b12ac99b5738cd199/Formula/h/hugo.rb">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/2fd8dba871a6a5412fa7c00b12ac99b5738cd199/Formula/h/hugo.rb&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replace the commit ID and app name accordingly to get the correct URL.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>According to some online guides, you can directly install using the URL with &lt;code>brew install url&lt;/code>.
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>However, when I tried this, I encountered an error: &lt;code>Error: Non-checksummed download of hugo formula file from an arbitrary URL is unsupported! brew extract or brew create and brew tap-new to create a formula file in a tap on GitHub instead.&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Instead, I copied the formula file’s content, saved it locally, and then installed it using &lt;code>brew install ./hugo.rb&lt;/code>. The installation was successful.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>After successfully downgrading the Homebrew application, you can lock the version using &lt;code>brew pin hugo&lt;/code> to prevent future upgrades.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>After encountering the failure with the &lt;code>install url&lt;/code> method, I found &lt;a href="https://www.ericbariaux.com/posts/brew_rollback/">another approach&lt;/a> for downgrading, which also seemed feasible. However, I ran into errors while executing the build script locally. Still, it might be worth referencing.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">4
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">brew tap-new &lt;span class="nv">$USER&lt;/span>/local-cmake
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">brew tap homebrew/core --force
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">brew extract --version&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>3.31.1 cmake &lt;span class="nv">$USER&lt;/span>/local-cmake
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">brew install &lt;span class="nv">$USER&lt;/span>/local-cmake/cmake@3.31.1
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>Here’s an explanation of these commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These four Homebrew commands aim to create a local tap and install a specific version of CMake. Let me explain each command:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-brew-tap-new-userlocal-cmake">1. &lt;code>brew tap-new $USER/local-cmake&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This command creates a new tap (software repository). &lt;code>$USER&lt;/code> is an environment variable representing the current username, so the tap will be named &amp;quot;your-username/local-cmake.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Purpose&lt;/strong>: Create a new local tap to store custom formulae.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Result&lt;/strong>: A new tap structure is created at &lt;code>$(brew --repo)/Library/Taps/$USER/homebrew-local-cmake&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2-brew-tap-homebrewcore---force">2. &lt;code>brew tap homebrew/core --force&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This command forcibly taps Homebrew's core repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Purpose&lt;/strong>: Ensure the homebrew/core repository (which contains official formulae) is properly tapped. The &lt;code>--force&lt;/code> flag ensures the action is performed even if the tap already exists.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Result&lt;/strong>: Ensures access to the formulae in homebrew/core, which is necessary for extracting the CMake formula.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="3-brew-extract---version3311-cmake-userlocal-cmake">3. &lt;code>brew extract --version=3.31.1 cmake $USER/local-cmake&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This command extracts a specific version of the CMake formula from homebrew/core to your local tap.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Purpose&lt;/strong>: Extract the CMake formula for version 3.31.1 from the official repository and place it in your newly created local tap.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Result&lt;/strong>: A &lt;code>cmake@3.31.1.rb&lt;/code> formula file is created in your local tap.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="4-brew-install-userlocal-cmakecmake3311">4. &lt;code>brew install $USER/local-cmake/cmake@3.31.1&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This command installs the specific version of CMake from your local tap.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Purpose&lt;/strong>: Use the extracted formula to install CMake version 3.31.1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Result&lt;/strong>: CMake version 3.31.1 is installed on your system.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tutorial/">Tutorial</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Experience/">Experience</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/macOS/">macOS</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Hugo/">Hugo</category></item><item><title>2024 Annual Record</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/record-of-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/record-of-2024/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:06:50 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>Having completed a full year as a pure worker, I'm writing a simple journal to record some events and thoughts from this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="january">January&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I finally went to Hong Kong to open a bank account. Although I encountered some unexpected problems - I discovered that &lt;a href="http://xhslink.com/a/Rb3xDU5JTPY2">my China Telecom SIM card had no signal when roaming in Hong Kong&lt;/a> - it was a close call, but I managed to successfully open the account and got the card on the spot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From this moment on, I also began my US stock investment journey. Through the channel of US stocks, I've had more thoughts about investing and making money. After starting work last year, I felt that making money was the most important thing, but I didn't have many ideas about how exactly to make money or how to have income outside of work. Now after getting into US stock investing, although it's impossible to make big money immediately through investing, at least I can see hope - especially after seeing some peers who switched careers to become full-time traders and are still able to support themselves and live well. This makes me feel that this path has potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The core is still: prepare well and wait for opportunities.&lt;/strong> Save more money, actively look for opportunities, be open, and don't limit yourself to just one path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taking advantage of the bank account opening trip, I also spent a day playing in Hong Kong. The last time I went to Hong Kong was probably during middle school. As a Cantonese person, although I've been exposed to a lot of information about Hong Kong and seem very familiar with it, this was actually only my second time there. However, knowing Cantonese and being familiar with Hong Kong culture meant I didn't encounter any problems while visiting. Hong Kong as a city still has many aspects that attract me, reminding me of my middle school aspiration to study at the University of Hong Kong. Now I actually have the opportunity to get an HKID and work in Hong Kong, but various factors make me hesitate, especially the &amp;quot;stay for seven years&amp;quot; threshold being too high. However, while living there might not work out, visiting more often is definitely possible. After my first trip to Hong Kong, I immediately updated my endorsement to multiple-entry upon returning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="february">February&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Chinese New Year - it feels less and less festive, maybe because I'm getting older and have less and less anticipation for it. New Year has gradually evolved into going back to the countryside to eat, visiting relatives and eating with them - various template-like scenes of eating meals everywhere. I don't really like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="march--april">March &amp;amp; April&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A project I owned was finally launching. During this period, external partner organizations caused all sorts of trouble and problems. Even after launch, there was still a lot of follow-up work needed. However, the final business results were extremely good - the launch brought in extremely high TPV for the year. Although technology is meant to serve business, a very realistic point is: after achieving good business results, will the credit really go to the technical staff? This reminds me of a complaint post I once saw on the internal network - at the celebration banquet, all kinds of people were present, except technical staff were nowhere to be seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Combined with the year-end bonus and salary adjustment after the annual performance review came out, it made me want to laugh even more &lt;del>(As a newcomer, I didn't even get that 500)&lt;/del> and made me realize even more that being a worker has no future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202501041125963.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>My girlfriend's graduate school entrance exam results also came out - high scores on the initial test, and after two weeks of preparation, she successfully passed the interview as well. Finally made it ashore - congratulations! This made up for the regret from back then.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="may">May&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Checked in to Shantou. Although I had many Chaoshan classmates in high school, this was my first time actually going there. My impression of Shantou is all about beef hotpot and licorice fruit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="june">June&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Went to Malaysia for a team building trip. Seven years since my last time abroad, and it was also to Malaysia again. The island scenery was indeed quite nice, and snorkeling was very interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traveling in Southeast Asia is really affordable - the round-trip airfare all-inclusive was only 900+. I'm gradually realizing that going abroad to travel isn't as complicated as I imagined, and the value for money is quite good. In the new year, I hope to have more opportunities to unlock different countries (but I'll need to unlock various countries' visas first).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="september---november">September - November&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In three months, I attended three classmates' weddings. Friends and classmates around me are gradually getting married and starting families. I have quite a lot of feelings about this - witnessing peers around me enter the next stage of life, occasionally I also wonder: when will it be my turn? I'm not afraid of marriage or having children; on the contrary, I actually look forward to marriage, family, and kids. However, getting married isn't that simple. Marriage means the union of two families - it's not just two people getting a marriage certificate and calling it done. There are all kinds of factors to consider. But troublesome as it may be, it still needs to be faced, and I won't run away from it. I hope this happy event can happen in the next couple of years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="december">December&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I put off the company's annual health checkup until the end of the year. Fortunately, the results showed no major problems. Since starting work, I feel like my body isn't as good as before. I used to often self-deprecatingly tell others that in our industry, we trade our lives for high salaries. Now that I'm actually working, I've found that work really is a form of wear and tear, both physiologically and psychologically. How to face this wear and tear and minimize its impact is the most important subject in my work life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest physiological impact is having less time for exercise. During school, I had plenty of time and exercised almost every day. Even if I didn't exercise, my daily walking was sufficient. But after starting work, it's easy to go a whole week without exercising (of course, part of the reason is that I'm too tired from work and too lazy to move). So I've been looking for an efficient exercise method that I can stick to, to get myself moving. I previously bought a kettlebell, and the exercise effect was indeed good - it could even be used as HIIT - but after persisting for a month, it was left idle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently this month I've picked up swimming again. Actually, I've loved swimming since I was little. During childhood summers, as soon as vacation started, my family would take me swimming, and I developed what I considered pretty good swimming skills. After starting university, I basically stopped swimming. Now after resuming swimming, I've started swimming in professional pools with lanes (the pools I swam in as a kid were really just big pools). After being around more swimmers and using my watch to record my swimming sessions, I've realized that I'm not actually that good at swimming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a small city, not that many people know how to swim, and the pools aren't that professional - most people going to &amp;quot;swim&amp;quot; are actually just playing in the water. Being the best swimmer in such an environment doesn't really mean anything. But when you're in it, your vision and thoughts are still limited by the environment and platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My former self was a bit like a frog at the bottom of a well - and this isn't just about swimming, but many other aspects too. I was limited by my own thinking, ideas, or various factors. I still need to open myself up, be open and keep exploring.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Record/">Record</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Summary/">Summary</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Life/">Life</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Investment/">Investment</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Work/">Work</category></item><item><title>Blog RSS Fetch Failed</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2024/rss-fetch-failed/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2024/rss-fetch-failed/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:50:22 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>Two weeks ago, I received an email from the maintainer of &lt;a href="https://github.com/nju-lug/blogroll">NJU-LUG Blogroll&lt;/a>, informing me that the RSS feed of my blog was not being fetched properly and suggesting I take a look when I had time. Since I hadn't updated my blog in the past two months and was too busy to check, I hadn't noticed the issue. After publishing a new post yesterday, I realized today that the view count was still zero. I opened &lt;a href="https://app.follow.is/share/feeds/55149012216215581">Follow&lt;/a> and found that Follow was also having trouble fetching the RSS feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I received the email, I tested the RSS feed locally, and it opened without any issues. Then I checked the error logs provided by NJU-LUG Blogroll, which indicated a timeout error. My initial guess was that there might be an issue with the CDN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I logged into Upyun to inspect the CDN settings and eventually discovered a configuration option for &lt;strong>Acceleration Regions&lt;/strong>. The default setting was &amp;quot;Domestic Acceleration,&amp;quot; which routes overseas requests to domestic CDN nodes. It seemed the problem lay here—overseas access (e.g., GitHub Action) might have been unable to reach Upyun's domestic CDN nodes recently, resulting in timeouts and the inability to fetch the RSS feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202412291319630.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After changing the configuration to &amp;quot;Global Acceleration,&amp;quot; I retried fetching the RSS feed in Follow, and the issue was resolved successfully.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Blog/">Blog</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/GitHub/">GitHub</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/rss/">rss</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Notes/">Notes</category></item></channel></rss>