<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>YeungYeah's Context</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/</link><description>Tinkering with code and tools, finding balance in anxiety.
No standard answers here, just the honest context of tech, reading, and life.</description><generator>Hugo 0.122.0 https://gohugo.io/</generator><language>en-US</language><managingEditor>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</managingEditor><webMaster>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:05:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://scottyeung.top/en/atom.xml"/><item><title>From Typing to Talking: My Adventures and Pitfalls with Voice Input</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/voice-input-experience/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/voice-input-experience/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:52:18 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>During the Spring Festival holiday, I came across a lot of posts about voice input. I decided to take the plunge and embrace AI even further, to see if I could max out my efficiency and productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I started trying out various voice input tools, forcing myself to switch my everyday input to &amp;quot;talking&amp;quot; mode. My current workflow mainly involves: using &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Lightning Say&amp;quot; (闪电说)&lt;/strong> combined with &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Doubao&amp;quot; (豆包)&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Tongyi Qianwen&amp;quot; (通义千问)&lt;/strong>'s streaming voice models for recognition and transcription.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For different output needs, my approach is as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Long-form text&lt;/strong>: I created a custom Gem in Gemini, and feed it the raw transcription to remove filler words and fix misrecognized words. Then I do a manual pass.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Short phrases/fragmented thoughts&lt;/strong>: Usually edit manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>My current verdict is: &lt;strong>accuracy is acceptable, but we're still far from true &amp;quot;productivity freedom.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong> In many scenarios, it's in a state of &amp;quot;unusable&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;not great.&amp;quot; Of course, this might be because the tools I'm using aren't powerful enough, or my technique is off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my trial so far, here are the most strongly &amp;quot;discouraging&amp;quot; experiences:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-scene-pickiness-not-just-about-environment-but-also-about-people">1. Scene Pickiness: Not Just About Environment, But Also About People&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Voice input is very &amp;quot;delicate.&amp;quot; If the environment is noisy, or there's video audio playing in the background, it captures all the noise indiscriminately, causing recognition to fall apart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, &lt;strong>social awkwardness&lt;/strong> is a major obstacle. Talking to your phone in public or outdoors involves privacy concerns and can disturb others. Compared to silently typing, typing is the most appropriate choice in those situations. For now, voice input seems limited to the absolute comfort zone of &amp;quot;home alone&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;private room&amp;quot; with no one around to interrupt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-recognition-accuracy-still-falls-short-of-think-it-get-it">2. Recognition Accuracy: Still Falls Short of &amp;quot;Think It, Get It&amp;quot;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Even with powerful large language models integrated, the recognition rate still hasn't reached the level where I can fully trust it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mixed Chinese-English input&lt;/strong> is a major pain point.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Proper nouns&lt;/strong> (names, places) are frequently misidentified.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This means even though &amp;quot;input&amp;quot; is faster, I still have to spend a lot of time on AI post-processing or manually &amp;quot;bug-hunting,&amp;quot; and the time saved gets eaten up again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-filler-word-literature-and-ai-over-dramatization">3. &amp;quot;Filler Word Literature&amp;quot; and AI Over-Dramatization&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The nature of voice input means it carries heavy colloquial characteristics. The thinking pauses, logical leaps, and slips of the tongue while speaking are all faithfully recorded by the software. Unlike typing, where we've already processed the logic mentally before our fingers hit the keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While large models can be used to &amp;quot;clean up&amp;quot; the text, that process itself is also a hassle. Take &amp;quot;Lightning Say&amp;quot; (闪电说) as an example — it provides a native text polishing feature based on large models. But in actual use, this AI was &lt;strong>&amp;quot;overly enthusiastic.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I originally just wanted to transcribe: &amp;quot;I want you to do certain things, investigate a certain problem.&amp;quot;
The AI took it upon itself to brainstorm and write out &amp;quot;the specific investigation steps&amp;quot; for me!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This kind of &amp;quot;fabricating from nothing&amp;quot; &lt;strong>hallucination&lt;/strong> is unacceptable to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I later tried modifying the prompt, emphasizing &amp;quot;absolutely do not add or remove content,&amp;quot; which helped somewhat, but it still can't be 100% faithful to the original words.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Furthermore, since it's a packaged feature, I can't see exactly what it changed (no diff comparison), and I can't fine-tune parameters, making this feature feel quite useless.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="4-lack-of-streaming-security">4. Lack of &amp;quot;Streaming&amp;quot; Security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Despite the underlying model being streaming, the software interaction doesn't support streaming display.
This forces me to speak a large chunk before seeing the final result. The process is like &lt;strong>&amp;quot;opening a mystery box&amp;quot;&lt;/strong> — if the beginning was misrecognized, I can't catch and correct it in time like I would when typing, and can only push through to the end, then face a pile of gibberish in utter despair.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="summary-bittersweet">Summary: Bittersweet&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Despite all these complaints, I have to admit: &lt;strong>in specific conditions, the efficiency boost is overwhelming.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I tried using OneNote to record my Spring Festival retrospective and produced over 1,000 characters. If typed by hand, it would take at least 30-40 minutes, but through voice dictation, &lt;strong>it only took about ten minutes&lt;/strong>. That rush of speed is genuinely addictive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among the issues above:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Recognition, interaction, over-processing&lt;/strong>: These are fundamentally issues of immature software and models. In theory, they can all be solved with future technological iteration (for example, once voiceprint recognition matures, it'll be able to only listen to the owner's voice and filter out background noise).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Environmental limitations&lt;/strong>: This is a physical reality — just like sending voice messages on WeChat, you have to read the room.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this era of large language models, I increasingly feel that &lt;strong>&amp;quot;content&amp;quot; itself matters more than &amp;quot;input perfection.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>
As long as the core ideas can be thrown out quickly, grammar, typos, and polish can all be left to AI to clean up. Especially in scenarios like writing diaries and weekly reviews that don't require intense logical construction, voice input is simply a godsend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the foreseeable future, I expect to continue &amp;quot;grinding&amp;quot; with this workflow. If anyone has a better solution, or is using some great voice input tool, feel free to recommend it in the comments!&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Complaints/">Complaints</category></item><item><title>Superpower Agent Skills in Gemini</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/superpower-skills-gemini/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/superpower-skills-gemini/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:42:07 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>While using Claude Code, the Skills suite provided by &lt;a href="https://github.com/obra/superpowers">superpowers&lt;/a> has been incredibly useful, especially Brainstorming, Writing-plans, and Executing-plans. After using these skills, you can clearly feel that the AI works more methodically with significantly improved logic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I've also been researching code Agent CLI tools beyond Claude Code. Since I have a Gemini subscription, I decided to try out Google's official CLI tool. Although Gemini CLI also supports Agent Skills, there are some differences in command formats and rule details compared to Claude. Currently, the official &lt;a href="https://github.com/obra/superpowers">superpowers&lt;/a> doesn't formally support Gemini (though I noticed there seems to be a related branch in development in the issue list).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rather than waiting passively, I decided to take matters into my own hands. So I decided to use Claude Code as a blueprint and migrate to create a Gemini version of &lt;code>superpowers&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project repository is now open source: &lt;a href="https://github.com/yeung66/gemini-superpowers">gemini-superpowers&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you'd like to try it out, you can quickly install it with the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">gemini skills install https://github.com/yeung66/gemini-superpowers.git --path skills
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="core-migration-content">Core Migration Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This migration mainly involved two parts of work: aligning tool names (Tools) and mapping core terminology (Terminology) to ensure Gemini can correctly understand and execute the original Agent logic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-tools-mapping">1. Tools Mapping&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We need to convert Claude Code's tool commands to equivalent commands that Gemini CLI can recognize:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Claude Code&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Gemini CLI&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Handling Method&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Task&lt;/code> (subagent dispatch)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Process description&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Change to &amp;quot;step-by-step execution&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;process tasks one by one&amp;quot;&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>TaskCreate&lt;/code>/&lt;code>TaskUpdate&lt;/code>/&lt;code>TaskList&lt;/code>/&lt;code>TaskGet&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>write_todos&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>TodoWrite&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>write_todos&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Skill&lt;/code> tool&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>@skill-name&lt;/code> or direct reference&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Adapt to Gemini syntax&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Read&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>ReadFile&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Edit&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Edit&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No change&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Write&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>WriteFile&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Bash&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Shell&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Glob&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>FindFiles&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Grep&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>SearchText&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>WebFetch&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>WebFetch&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No change&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>WebSearch&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>GoogleSearch&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>AskUserQuestion&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>ask_user&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Direct replacement&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="2-terminology-mapping">2. Terminology Mapping&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To make the prompts more suitable for Gemini's context, some terms were also localized accordingly:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Claude Code&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Gemini CLI&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>your human partner&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>the user&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>CLAUDE.md&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>GEMINI.md&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>~/.claude/skills&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>~/.gemini/skills&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>superpowers:skill-name&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>skill-name&lt;/code> (remove prefix)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="usage-results">Usage Results&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After the migration was completed, these Skills can be perfectly loaded in Gemini CLI. In actual conversations, Gemini can accurately identify my development intentions and automatically invoke the corresponding tools to assist with work. The experience is basically consistent with &lt;code>superpowers&lt;/code> on Claude Code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're also a Gemini user, feel free to try it out and provide feedback!&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category></item><item><title>Cyber "Multiple Nationalities": A Record of Account Hassles</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/apple-google-multiple-accounts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/apple-google-multiple-accounts/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:18:02 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>I've been wanting to talk about accounts lately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This thing was originally just an identity marker, but in today's internet environment, it has forced us into becoming &amp;quot;cunning rabbits with three burrows.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a mainland China user, in the early years, to download some apps not available in the CN region, most of us probably prepared a Hong Kong region Apple ID as backup. Back then, I thought the HK ID was pretty perfect—Chinese interface, convenient payment (just link an Alipay HK or a Hong Kong bank card), and most of the services you'd need were available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the past two years, the AI era has arrived, and the situation has changed again. Many AI services (like Claude, ChatGPT's iOS clients) are not only locked in the CN region, but even HK region has been categorized as &amp;quot;not supported.&amp;quot; No choice—to keep up with the times, I had to bite the bullet and get a US region Apple ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn't just happening on iOS; Android isn't any better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I originally thought having a Hong Kong region Google account would be enough—the Play Store has complete content, and there are no payment obstacles. But then Google's own child Gemini came out and immediately imposed regional restrictions. To smoothly use Gemini, I was forced to register a new US region Google account to subscribe to the membership.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now the situation has become quite surreal:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>iOS side&lt;/strong>: CN ID for storing photos, HK ID for downloading games, US ID for serving those picky AI Apps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Android side&lt;/strong>: HK account for downloading daily apps and using various Google services, US account specifically to serve Gemini.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Daily use is absolutely schizophrenic. On iPhone, to update an app I have to switch accounts, typing passwords until my fingers go numb; on Android, although switching is slightly more convenient, constantly switching back and forth for different service permissions, I often can't figure out which &amp;quot;country&amp;quot; I'm currently in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-ip-address-thing-is-even-more-mystical-than-accounts">The IP Address Thing Is Even More Mystical Than Accounts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Having a US region account doesn't mean you can use US region services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your network environment must be &amp;quot;clean.&amp;quot; This forces us to set up dedicated proxy rules for specific services. Before, one node could handle everything, but not anymore: this service requires a native US IP, that streaming service must use a residential broadband IP, another AI service blocks common data center IP ranges...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One slight slip of the hand, a routing rule written wrong, or a node drifting to a risk-controlled network segment, and at best the service becomes unavailable, at worst it directly triggers the risk control system. The worst case scenario is that due to IP changes being too frequent or locations being abnormal, your painstakingly registered account gets banned along with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time before opening these apps, I have to nervously confirm the proxy status, afraid of stepping into thin air and losing the account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="apple-id-registration-pitfall-guide">Apple ID Registration Pitfall Guide&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Google account registration is relatively forgiving, but the US Apple ID registration process is now practically a &amp;quot;battlefield.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First is the email issue. Apple ID is tightly bound to email, so three IDs take up three slots. After digging up some obscure email to register with, filling out a bunch of information, at the final step a popup directly appears:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;quot;Your account cannot be created at this time.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>No error code, no specific reason, just telling you &amp;quot;no.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unwilling to give up, changing the time, changing the IP, changing the browser—most likely still the same message. After searching online for a while, I found this is almost a common problem, probably triggering some mystical risk control mechanism of Apple's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After an afternoon of tinkering with no results, I later saw a folk remedy in some corner: &lt;strong>register using WeChat Mini Program&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With a &amp;quot;dead horse as a living horse doctor&amp;quot; mentality, I tried it, and it actually passed in one go! The path is roughly: search for Apple's official Mini Program (or related service entry) in WeChat, go through the account creation process inside. The risk control here seems much more lenient than the webpage and phone settings, no errors at all, smoothly passed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-pitfall-of-region-switching">The Pitfall of Region Switching&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The ID registered through the Mini Program defaults to &lt;strong>Mainland China&lt;/strong> region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought this would be easy—just change the region on the Apple ID webpage? But I hit another wall—modifying the region on the webpage, selecting United States, filling in the information, clicking save, error. Still an error without any reason given.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, the only option is to resort to the &amp;quot;hard change&amp;quot; method: &lt;strong>log into the new account directly in the App Store on your phone&lt;/strong>. The system will prompt you that this account has never been used and needs to be reviewed. After clicking review, on this interface select region as United States, agree to the terms. Magically, there's no obstacle here at all, and it directly lets you proceed to fill in the address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the address filling step, don't just fill in randomly. Although they don't verify actual residence, the zip code and state need to match.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two Tips:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use a generator&lt;/strong>: Google &amp;quot;US Address Generator,&amp;quot; there are tons of them, capable of generating complete information including street, phone number, and zip code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Choose a tax-free state&lt;/strong>: This step is very critical. If you plan to buy apps or subscribe to services in the future, make sure to choose an address in a &lt;strong>Tax-Free State&lt;/strong>. For example, &lt;strong>Oregon (OR)&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Delaware (DE)&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Montana (MT)&lt;/strong>, etc. Otherwise, buying a $19.99 software, you'll have to pay extra tax. Although it's not much money, it's annoying.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="heading">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After going through all this hassle, looking at those accounts from different regions on my phone, I let out a long sigh of relief.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this digital age, wanting to get a bit of convenience that should have been there all along (like using Gemini, downloading ChatGPT), often requires a disproportionate amount of time investment. The four or five accounts clutched in hand, plus that pile of complex network rules, is probably the most authentic portrait of our generation of netizens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes I wonder, these should be the most basic services, why do they have to be made so complicated? But wondering is wondering, the tinkering that needs to be done still needs to be done. After all, in this era, not tinkering means falling behind.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Apple/">Apple</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Google/">Google</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Rant/">Rant</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tinkering/">Tinkering</category></item><item><title>Translating Blog Posts with Claude Skills</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/claude-skills-to-translate/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/claude-skills-to-translate/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:28:54 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>I previously set up an &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/en/">English version&lt;/a> of my blog (the process is documented in &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/2024/setup-english-blog/">Setting Up My English Blog with Hugo&lt;/a>), where I publish some articles translated into English using AI. The original workflow was: after writing an article, I would paste it into a large language model's chat window, use a fixed prompt to translate it into English while maintaining the same markdown format, then copy the output and create a new file in the corresponding directory for English content. This involved copying and pasting several times and manually creating new files each time. It was fairly quick, but after getting familiar with Claude Code, I wondered if I could make it even more convenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I decided to use &lt;a href="https://code.claude.com/docs/en/skills#create-your-first-skill">Claude Skills&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is a Claude Skill?
Skills are modular, self-contained extension packages that expand Claude's capabilities by providing specialized knowledge, workflows, and tools. Think of them as &amp;quot;onboarding guides&amp;quot; for specific domains or tasks—they transform Claude from a general-purpose agent into a specialized agent equipped with procedural knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>By defining a SKILL.md document, you can create a skill that describes the execution steps and instructions, along with external executable code and reference materials. With a single command, you can have Claude Code perform the corresponding operations. Taking blog translation as an example, I created a SKILL.md file in the &lt;code>./claude/skills/translate-post&lt;/code> directory of my project with the following content:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt"> 1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 4
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 5
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 6
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 7
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 8
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt"> 9
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">10
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">11
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-md" data-lang="md">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">---
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">name: translate-post
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">description: transalte post&amp;#39;s content from Chinese into English
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">disable-model-invocation: true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">---
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">transalte the specific post file $ARGUMENTS content into English
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">1.&lt;/span> read file $ARGUMENTS all text content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">2.&lt;/span> translate all content into English. cannot drop any content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">3.&lt;/span> create a text file in content_en directory but with the same path with original file in content
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>Very simple instructions: read the file content, translate it into English, and create a file in the specified directory. Here, $ARGUMENTS is the input parameter. When actually running it, you just need to enter the command &lt;code>/translate-post @content/posts/2026/post.md&lt;/code>, and Claude Code will automatically create a file with the same name under &lt;code>content_en/posts/2026/&lt;/code>, with the translated content inside.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Blog/">Blog</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Automation/">Automation</category></item><item><title>Truly Embracing AI</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/embrace-ai-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/embrace-ai-again/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:50:08 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>Claude Code has been around and popular for a while now. When it first came out, I actually tried it using the API mode, but at that time I found it rather clumsy. Back then, CC got stuck on common network issues while installing dependencies, and the process was interrupted at the very first step. Plus, the token consumption was too intense to afford on my own, so I didn't pay much attention to it afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, my company has started promoting Claude Code internally, providing a free monthly token quota and corresponding internal API access. We can now use Claude Code at work, and some team members have been sharing their experiences with it. So this week I tried using Claude Code at work, but the internal rate limiting was too aggressive. I could feel its power, but the user experience was just average.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So these past two days I started using Claude Code on my personal projects. At first, I was thinking about whether I could use it for free, learning from the company's approach by finding some free tokens and then using Claude Code through the API. Both Doubao and Qianwen work for this - basically every provider now gives some token quota when you create a new account and generate an API Key. Doubao gives 500K, and then you can get several million tokens by completing some tasks. Qianwen gives 1 million tokens. The experience is actually quite decent, but the token consumption is still pretty fast. After two days with Doubao, I had already used about 6 million tokens, and continuing would require payment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I'd have to pay anyway, I might as well go all in and try the genuine, native Claude Code. I had just switched to a better VPN service with good US nodes, so using it shouldn't be a problem. So I looked for ways to subscribe. Unfortunately, Anthropic doesn't support domestic credit cards for payment - you can only pay through third-party virtual cards or gift cards. I ended up choosing services from &lt;a href="https://meiguo.app/">Meiguo&lt;/a>. Initially, I knew they offered credit card services, but later I found out they also provide gift card services directly. Claude Code Pro only requires a +$4 service fee and supports WeChat payment, which is very convenient. I got one, received the gift card via email, and used it to activate the membership myself. If you're interested, give it a try using my &lt;a href="https://meiguo.app?ref=O63O3">referral code O63O3&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After switching to the genuine native Claude Code, the experience went up another level. The official version feels like a smarter model with stronger development capabilities, and the development ideas and plans it outputs are clearer and more precise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've actually been in contact with AI and large language models for quite some time. When ChatGPT first came out, I was already using it - you could say I've been keeping up with the latest developments all along. But I feel like I've always just been scratching the surface. For new things, I try them once, think they're amazing, marvel at them for a moment, or find them not useful and complain a bit, and then that's it. Even the amazing and useful ones, I don't continue using them or integrate them into my work and life. The not-so-useful ones, I don't think about how to make them useful or how to actually use them. I vaguely sense that I might be gradually falling behind in this era of intelligence. Especially when I see more and more people around me starting to do vibe coding, or using AI and large language models for various things, I start comparing and getting anxious. I really need to use it more, use it in all kinds of ways, use it in daily life, use it at work, and integrate it into life.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/AI/">AI</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Coding/">Coding</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Software/">Software</category></item><item><title>Investing with Alpha Picks</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/use-alpha-picks-invest/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/use-alpha-picks-invest/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:51:10 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>My previous individual stock investments have always lacked a proper methodology. In the middle of last year, I studied some concepts of value investing and learned about company valuation analysis and stock selection methods, but with limited energy and time, and perhaps limited skill level, I ultimately didn't spend much time carefully researching individual stocks. It then evolved into watching YouTube or other platforms - whoever mentioned a certain stock, I'd take a look and buy it based on feeling. When to buy, how much to buy, when to add to positions, when to sell - all based on feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized I needed to create my own trading system. No matter how good or bad, it's better than doing things randomly. The domestic fund DCA investments have basically formed a fixed plan and don't need much attention anymore. For US stocks, during last year's Black Friday, I purchased a Seeking Alpha premium membership and their Alpha Picks service. This post is a record of my attempts to explore and use Alpha Picks for investing during this period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-alpha-picks">What is Alpha Picks?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Alpha Picks is a paid stock-picking service launched by Seeking Alpha. Based on collected data, it uses quantitative methods to select two stocks per month for users. The stocks it has selected have achieved returns of 270+% to date, which is more than 3 times the S&amp;amp;P 500 index.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260109231402620.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The official portfolio operation logic is: at the beginning and middle of each month, a new STRONG BUY stock is added with a fixed position size purchased. Then when the stock's quantitative rating drops to below SELL, or drops to HOLD for 180 days, it will be sold.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-should-new-users-use-it">How Should New Users Use It?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When new users now activate Alpha Picks, there are already dozens of stocks in the portfolio. The official recommendation is to pick 5 STRONG BUY stocks to purchase, or directly buy the entire portfolio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through communication with Gemini, Gemini provided an operation guide for reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fZ_0du3qfKGU_5BtFEgDxOBwa5TEQMjC5yLwj_wXsc0/edit?usp=sharing">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fZ_0du3qfKGU_5BtFEgDxOBwa5TEQMjC5yLwj_wXsc0/edit?usp=sharing&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>As an ordinary investor, if you want to make money by following Alpha Picks, &lt;strong>you shouldn't pursue 100% perfect mechanical replication, but rather grasp its core logic and adopt a simplified execution plan&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a best practices guide for ordinary investors:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-core-mindset-execute-like-a-machine-trust-the-system">1. Core Mindset: Execute Like a Machine (Trust the System)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is the hardest part. Alpha Picks is based on quantitative data (Quant Ratings), and its stock selection logic is often counterintuitive.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Situations you may encounter:&lt;/strong> It recommends an obscure stock you've never heard of, or a stock that you think has already risen too much, or even from an industry you personally dislike (such as coal, or even certain consumer stocks).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What to do:&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Pinch your nose and buy.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong> If you've subscribed to this service, trust its algorithm. The biggest source of losses for ordinary investors often comes from &amp;quot;I feel this stock isn't good&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;This stock has risen too high, I dare not buy.&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="2-position-building-phase-how-to-start-getting-started">2. Position Building Phase: How to Start? (Getting Started)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you just subscribed today, facing 30+ historical holdings, how do you buy?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Official/Ideal advice:&lt;/strong> Buy the entire portfolio according to current weights.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ordinary person/Realistic advice:&lt;/strong> With limited funds, don't buy all 30.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Strategy:&lt;/strong> Only buy the top 5-10 stocks currently rated &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Strong Buy&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reason:&lt;/strong> Although those early &amp;quot;winners&amp;quot; have risen a lot, if their current rating has dropped to &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot;, there's no need to chase highs to build positions now. Only buy those with the strongest current data.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="3-daily-operations-twice-monthly-new-stock-day-the-monthly-routine">3. Daily Operations: Twice-Monthly &amp;quot;New Stock Day&amp;quot; (The Monthly Routine)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Alpha Picks usually has two new recommendations (Picks) per month.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Capital allocation:&lt;/strong> Try to ensure that the amount invested each time is roughly the same (Equal Weighting).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Wrong approach:&lt;/em> This month I have money, buy $2000; next month I don't have money, only buy $200. This will cause your performance to be dominated by the stock with the large position.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Correct approach:&lt;/em> Set a fixed &amp;quot;monthly contribution&amp;quot; amount. For example, DCA $1000 per month, $500 for each new stock. If there's surplus, save it for the next time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="4-selling-rules-strictly-follow-discipline-selling-rules">4. Selling Rules: Strictly Follow Discipline (Selling Rules)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is the key to Alpha Picks outperforming the market — &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Let profits run, cut losses short.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When to sell?&lt;/strong> Only sell when you receive an official email notification. There are usually two situations:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rating plunge:&lt;/strong> The stock rating directly drops to &lt;strong>Sell&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Strong Sell&lt;/strong> — &lt;strong>Sell immediately&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rating stagnation:&lt;/strong> The stock rating drops to &lt;strong>Hold&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>remains at Hold for 180 consecutive days&lt;/strong> — &lt;strong>Sell&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note:&lt;/em> Many ordinary investors panic and want to sell when they see it become &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot; - this is wrong. Alpha Picks allows stocks to adjust in &amp;quot;Hold&amp;quot; status for half a year, which often captures subsequent gains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sell regardless of profit or loss:&lt;/strong> Even if you've lost 40% on this stock, if the system says sell, you must sell (stop loss); even if you've made 200% on this stock, if the system hasn't said sell, don't sell just to &amp;quot;lock in gains&amp;quot; (not only to let profits run, but also to avoid missing the main upward wave).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="5-capital-reinvestment-simplify-your-life-simplifying-reinvestment">5. Capital Reinvestment: Simplify Your Life (Simplifying Reinvestment)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Back to the capital handling issue you're most concerned about.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Don't:&lt;/strong> Every time you sell a stock, take out your calculator and split a few hundred dollars evenly among the remaining 20 stocks. This will create a lot of fractional shares and tax headaches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Do:&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Capital pool&amp;quot; strategy&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you sell a stock (say you recoup $1000), or receive a dividend (say $50), treat all this money as &lt;strong>&amp;quot;ammunition for the next purchase&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Directly invest this money into the &lt;strong>next recommended new stock&lt;/strong>, or add to the current &lt;strong>top 3 Strong Buy&lt;/strong> stocks.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="summary-the-lazy-protocol-for-ordinary-investors">Summary: The &amp;quot;Lazy Protocol&amp;quot; for Ordinary Investors&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Operation Step&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Official Complex Instructions&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Recommended Approach for Ordinary People&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>What to buy&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Configure entire portfolio by weight&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Only buy &lt;strong>latest recommendations&lt;/strong> + current highest-rated &lt;strong>Strong Buys&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>How much to buy&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Strictly equal split&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Try to use &lt;strong>fixed amounts&lt;/strong> (e.g., $500 per stock), no need to be too precise&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Sale proceeds&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Split evenly among all remaining holdings&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Save it&lt;/strong>, buy the next two newly recommended stocks in full&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Dividends&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Split evenly among all remaining holdings&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Save it&lt;/strong>, accumulate enough to buy new stocks, or enable automatic reinvestment (DRIP)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Mindset&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rational quantitative&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Even if the stock is ugly or you don't know it, &lt;strong>buy with eyes closed&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Following this simplified strategy, you can capture 95%+ of Alpha Picks' returns, but reduce operational complexity by 90%.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Investment/">Investment</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Notes/">Notes</category></item><item><title>2025 Annual Record</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/record-of-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2026/record-of-2025/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>As per my annual tradition, I'm reviewing 2025 through a journal-style account and recording some thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/Gemini_Generated_Image_6z6pef6z6pef6z6p.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timeline">Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="january">January&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The BU and team started mass recruiting contractors to become the main force for project implementation going forward. Full-time employees needed to become so-called &amp;quot;architects&amp;quot; leading the contractors. Setting aside whether I, someone who had only been with the company for a year and a half, was qualified to be a so-called architect - in upper management's view, throwing more people at problems solves everything. Full-time employees too expensive? Then pile on contractors. Can the contractors handle it? Even if they can't, someone has to lead them. Even if efficiency is low, as long as the base number is large, it's still better than zero. So the boss started leading a contractor team, which gradually expanded to several times the size of the full-time employee count. Later, each full-time employee led several contractors, ultimately becoming a &amp;quot;labor contractor.&amp;quot; For someone like me who had only been out of campus recruitment for two years, is being a labor contractor really a good thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, taking advantage of this contractor recruitment opportunity, I went to Changsha twice in January for communication and guidance with them. Changsha is a nice place. Although I didn't get to go anywhere fun during the business trip, the food was decent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I went home for Spring Festival, the family's new house was ready to move into. We moved to another residential complex with a better environment, bigger rooms, and easier parking spaces - very comfortable. Especially after the parking upgrade, I no longer need to ask my father for help parking the car when I drive back.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="march">March&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On the first day of March, while playing in Hong Kong, I suddenly saw news that Khalil Fong had passed away. Several people messaged me about it. As a long-time fan of Khalil Fong, my first reaction was bewilderment and disbelief - he had just made a comeback last year, released a new album, and appeared on shows, and suddenly I see such terrible news. Besides feeling sad for him, I increasingly felt that life is impermanent. Nothing truly lasts forever; people really can die suddenly, regardless of age or status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the month, after performance reviews came out, I got my first good rating and promotion. However, looking at that bit of year-end bonus and salary increase, I felt it was just so-so. Even though this was called the best year, the money wasn't that much - especially comparing the year-end bonus between good and average performance ratings, the extra two months wasn't that much more money. I don't know what the point is (though maybe it's because my base salary isn't high enough). Also, I've always found it rather absurd that promotion is tied to performance. Promotion should mean your abilities have reached the next level, so promotion makes your level match your ability. However, performance only reflects the year's work - whether you met or exceeded expectations. The two aren't really related. I've even often seen lower-level employees assigned higher-level work and used as higher-level employees, but when it comes to performance reviews, because they're doing higher-level work, their targets and expectations are higher, resulting in not getting good performance ratings and naturally no promotion. It all depends on the boss's conscience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="april---june">April - June&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During Labor Day holiday, my girlfriend and I went to Kunming. It was my first time back in Yunnan since graduating from elementary school. Kunming's weather is really comfortable, and Yunnan cuisine and mushrooms are delicious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June, the team outing was to Chongzuo, Guangxi again. Originally we considered keeping it relaxed and not too intense, but in the end it felt too relaxed - we didn't really go anywhere fun, and ultimately just played cards heavily with colleagues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going out to play was quite fun, although work was still there. Unfortunately, I still couldn't completely disconnect during holidays. Before, it was more about not daring to, afraid of being escalated. Now it's become more about worrying that things might go wrong or progress might stall, so I proactively check even during holidays.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="august---november">August - November&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The company planned to focus heavily on the Brazilian market, and the big boss suddenly thought about sending us tech people to Brazil for local support. Honestly, I don't understand what a tech person can accomplish by going to Brazil for a two-month business trip, but it was the boss's idea, and we could only comply. Initially, the manager collected everyone's preferences to see if anyone would volunteer. But obviously no one did - the time difference, security issues, language barrier, and long distance were all very discouraging factors. Eventually it became a rotation within the team - the manager went first, I was in the second batch, and even +2 couldn't avoid it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101200933342.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After it was confirmed I was going, it was all kinds of preparations - applying for visa, booking flights, reserving hotels. During this process, I kept receiving all sorts of negative information about Brazil from social media and colleagues already stationed there - like poor security, poor infrastructure. The main concern was the security issue, with various thefts and robberies. I even saw a post during National Day about a Huawei employee being shot and their laptop stopping the bullet and saving their life. Really scary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this mindset, I departed for Brazil with another colleague after National Day, flying over twenty hours total before landing in São Paulo. Then, being overly cautious - maybe I was dizzy from the flight - when I took an Uber from the airport to the hotel, I left my backpack in the car. It wasn't until over two hours later, after checking in and eating, that I realized I had left my backpack in the car - with my two laptops and an iPad inside. Although I immediately tried to contact the Uber driver, Uber's lost and found mechanism is absolutely ridiculous. You can't get the driver's contact information to reach them directly; you can only wait for the platform to forward your message to the driver, then have the driver reply to the platform to forward back to you. With all this back and forth, the driver didn't reply until the next morning. Plus, electronic products are really expensive locally in Brazil, so I never got it back. Filing a police report only got me a report receipt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So my Brazil business trip started catastrophically - I lost all electronic devices except my phone right after landing, including my work computer and personal computer (two MacBook Pros). Losing the devices, my first reaction was actually heartache over the money, but my immediate thought was: my computer is gone, how am I supposed to work?? I had already accumulated two days of work matters during the flight, and now my computer was gone. Fortunately, I managed to get help from local IT and borrowed a computer. The tough part was that the loaner was only a Windows laptop - an old 2019 Dell notebook - but I had to make do. In the end, I got through it. Despite the time difference and crappy equipment, there were no major problems with work, I adapted well to life there, and I didn't encounter any security issues afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting aside the accident and work, the Brazil business trip was actually quite interesting. Although security wasn't great, as long as you don't go out at night, only take taxis when going out, and don't look at your phone outside, you basically don't encounter major problems. In distant São Paulo, I experienced quite a few new things and ate a lot of food - even ate quite authentic Chinese food. One Sichuan restaurant could even rival many restaurants back in China. Also, the two-month business trip incidentally earned me Marriott Platinum and Hilton Diamond status, and I started consciously building up hotel memberships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this Brazil trip, I became even more aware that my English really isn't good enough, especially in speaking. Communicating with local colleagues was rather strained and difficult. I've been learning English all along, but I've never reached a level that satisfies me, which is really a pity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="december">December&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After returning from Brazil, since all my devices were lost, I had to buy new ones. I was previously all-in on the Apple ecosystem and had been wanting to leave it, but if I bought another MacBook Pro + iPad, I'd be spending another 20k RMB, which I couldn't bear. So I switched to an Android tablet + Windows laptop and gradually adapted. I also gradually realized that these are just tools - basically anything can achieve the goal and meet requirements, it's just a matter of how smooth it feels. Of course, switching ecosystems was also because I wanted to experience something new.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thoughts">Thoughts&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="work--life">Work &amp;amp; Life&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As work becomes increasingly busy and high-pressure, work's proportion in life and its invasion into life has also increased. For example, in this year's annual review, most of it is actually work or work-related matters. There aren't many personal or life matters, and even the second half of the year was mainly due to the Brazil business trip. It's rather sad - work is gradually alienating me. The few days before New Year's, I actually took three days off to piece together an eight-day mini vacation, but I couldn't stop worrying about various projects. Even after turning off notifications, I still worried about work issues or if someone was looking for me, so I'd occasionally check in and reply to messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work is becoming less and less interesting, not just because of the complaints mentioned above. During work, I increasingly feel the &amp;quot;cog in the machine&amp;quot; nature of technology. Business is the core; BD is way more important than tech. No matter how fancy the tech is, it's useless without business - no one will use it. For example, in the payment acquiring field, no matter how many features you provide, it's not as good as lowering the fees a bit more. Technology becomes &amp;quot;basic&amp;quot; at this point, and basic things naturally have difficulty arguing for value since everyone has them. Maybe all jobs at big companies are like this. I hope to experience a different work environment. If there are good job opportunities, feel free to contact me 🤣&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="money--investment">Money &amp;amp; Investment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Work is boring; making money is the core. After opening a US stock account last year, riding the overall upward trend, I made a little profit in stocks. This year I also increased my principal investment and am accumulating and investing through different strategies across various accounts. However, in stock trading, I still haven't formed a trading system. Maybe I watched a few videos with analysis saying a certain stock is undervalued and bought in, then kept adding to the position as it went lower, and ended up deeply trapped. Investing is really a very professional matter that requires continuous time investment to learn. But under the current high-intensity work situation, the time and energy I invest in US stocks is actually decreasing. Maybe the ultimate destination is still the path of accumulating money through index funds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides individual US stocks, this year I've been continuously adjusting my DCA approach for index ETFs. Initially, I just randomly DCA'd into NASDAQ and S&amp;amp;P 500 on Alipay. After opening the US stock account, I also bought some on-exchange ETFs there. But later I realized that for DCA into indices, domestic QDII funds would suffice, so there's no need to do it in the US stock account. Then in the second half of the year, NASDAQ suddenly became hot in the public eye again, and everyone started DCA into NASDAQ. Off-exchange funds started limiting quotas one after another - limits of fifty or a hundred, even some limiting to 10 yuan per day, which is ridiculous. Then some simply stopped accepting subscriptions, so these past two months I've shifted to on-exchange funds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101211346636.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking back at the overall returns: Alipay funds made 9 percentage points, US stocks are still down 2 percentage points. Either way, both underperformed the broader market. Need to work harder and adjust more carefully next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this process, I started regularly recording all assets this year - how much is in each account, how much in total. I set up a Google Sheet and record it once a month. Through this numerical recording method, I can very clearly see the changes in my savings. Saving money really isn't easy - maybe I'm just not earning enough. I'm still working toward saving my first million RMB, hoping to achieve it early this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The more I write, the more I feel like work has brought me too much negative energy, haha. The annual review and summary seems to have turned into a complaint session. Complaining is useless; I still need to do something to make a change. I've been reading &lt;a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/32567134/">&lt;em>The Compound Effect&lt;/em>&lt;/a> recently, which mentions that even doing small things, as long as you persist, will eventually be effective. In the new year, whether it's saving money, learning English, or life in general, I hope to do a little bit more every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/20260101211407117.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Record/">Record</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Summary/">Summary</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Life/">Life</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Investment/">Investment</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Work/">Work</category></item><item><title>Scoop Install Specific Version App</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/scoop-install-specific-version-app/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/scoop-install-specific-version-app/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:36:07 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>After switching to the Windows environment and re-setting up some software, when pulling back my blog and setting up hugo, I encountered &lt;a href="https://scottyeung.top/2025/degrade-homebrew-app-version/">the same issue as before where the hugo version was too high and incompatible with my local blog theme&lt;/a>, requiring me to downgrade hugo to a specific version. In the macOS environment, applications are managed through Homebrew; in Windows, this is done through Scoop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I asked Gemini, and the response was that Scoop, like Homebrew, doesn't support installing specific versions of applications, but you can install older versions by specifying a URL to a specific manifest file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So you just need to go to Scoop's software repository, find the manifest file for the corresponding application, view the commit history, and find the source file URL for the historical version.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to Scoop's GitHub repository (usually &lt;a href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/tree/master/bucket">ScoopMain&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/tree/master/bucket">ScoopExtras&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the &lt;code>.json&lt;/code> file for the corresponding software (e.g., &lt;code>nodejs.json&lt;/code>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>History&lt;/strong> in the upper right corner to view commit history.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the commit record for the version you want and click to view the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Raw&lt;/strong> button and copy the URL from the browser address bar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>The URL looks like this:&lt;/em> &lt;code>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/.../commit_hash/.../app.json&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then install using this URL. Installing by specifying the manifest URL this way means the installed app cannot be updated - the version is automatically locked.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop install https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/4e72c5167244e249bbb063a93c28bb8aac034682/bucket/hugo-extended.json
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>However, finding historical versions of manifest files this way is actually very troublesome - you need to flip through page by page, and if the version is older, you'll have to flip for quite a while. After searching, I found that Scoop actually does support downloading specific versions of applications. After downloading a specific version, you can use the hold command to prevent updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">4
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="c1"># Install specific version&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop install &amp;lt;app&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="c1"># The scoop hold command prevents apps from being updated.&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">scoop hold &amp;lt;apps&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;p>Actually, this command can be seen in Scoop's help command. Gemini was a bit unreliable - even after I discovered that downloading specific versions was possible, it still stubbornly refused to admit it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/%7B0C842582-CFE1-488E-A12E-C0A4F71AA517%7D.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Windows/">Windows</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Experience/">Experience</category></item><item><title>Logseq Remove Blank Journal Pages</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-remove-blank-journals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/logseq-remove-blank-journals/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 12:38:08 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;p>When Logseq opens, it automatically creates a Journal page for the current day. Normally, when opening Logseq, you probably do want to make a record most of the time, so this feature seems fine. However, if Logseq isn't completely exited after opening, it will still create Journal pages every day as usual. Over time, when you open Logseq, you'll see a bunch of blank pages, which is very annoying, and it also makes browsing previous Journal entries very inconvenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To avoid this situation, I used to remind myself to press Command + Q to completely exit Logseq after using it, and for the occasional times I forgot, I would manually delete the blank pages. But in reality, it's very easy to forget to exit, and then maybe because of work, I wouldn't open it again for a week, accumulating a bunch of blank pages at once. Manually deleting them one by one is also quite tedious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, I thought about simply writing a script to scan for blank markdown files in the directory, but when I opened the local directory, I found that blank Journal pages don't necessarily create blank files. Later, I searched online and discovered that there's actually a built-in removal function for this, and the removal scope isn't limited to just blank Journals - all blank Pages can be scanned and removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specific path to the feature: All pages -&amp;gt; ... -&amp;gt; Remove orphaned pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202508311310890.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202508311310930.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Software/">Software</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Logseq/">Logseq</category></item><item><title>Self-hosted Bitwarden Suddenly Unavailable</title><link>https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/bitwarden-self-host-problem/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://scottyeung.top/en/2025/bitwarden-self-host-problem/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 14:46:50 +0800</pubDate><author>yeungyeah@qq.com (YeungYeah)</author><description>&lt;h2 id="foreword-my-configuration">Foreword: My Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have always been a loyal Bitwarden user. For data freedom, controllability, and to save money, I chose to self-host the service. My entire configuration was as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Server&lt;/strong>: Tencent Cloud Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password Service&lt;/strong>: Vaultwarden (Rust implementation of Bitwarden) Docker image&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Domain&lt;/strong>: Personal domain hosted on Tencent Cloud&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Client&lt;/strong>: Bitwarden clients across all platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reverse Proxy&lt;/strong>: Caddy, handling HTTPS automatically&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This combination had been running stably until today...&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-discovery-of-the-problem">1. Discovery of the Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, as usual, I opened the Bitwarden App on my phone to add a new login item. But strangely, after I clicked save, I couldn't find the newly added item in the list no matter how I looked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, I thought it was a bug in the App, but to be safe, I opened the desktop client to try adding it. The client directly prompted me that the &lt;strong>save failed&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I realized the problem might not be that simple; it was highly likely that the interface communication between the client and my server had gone wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-the-path-of-investigation">2. The Path of Investigation&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-preliminary-diagnosis-certificate-expiration">1. Preliminary Diagnosis: Certificate Expiration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The first thing I thought of was to check my Vaultwarden management page. I accessed it via the domain name and found the first problem:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>HTTP Access&lt;/strong>: Directly intercepted by Tencent Cloud, with a prompt saying &amp;quot;This website is not registered according to the relevant legal rules of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>HTTPS Access&lt;/strong>: The page could be opened, but the browser address bar clearly displayed an &amp;quot;Insecure&amp;quot; warning—the SSL certificate had expired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://scottyeung.top/my-images/202507191449467.png" alt="Browser certificate expiration warning">
&lt;em>(Image: Tencent Cloud intercepting the page due to lack of registration)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Case closed? It seemed quite likely. The expired certificate caused the HTTPS request of the API interface to fail, so the client naturally couldn't save data normally.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-deep-dive-why-didnt-caddy-auto-renew">2. Deep Dive: Why Didn't Caddy Auto-renew?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>But a new question followed: I use Caddy precisely because it can automatically implement HTTPS, applying for and renewing certificates. Why did it fail this time? Even stranger, other service domains on the same server could be accessed normally with valid certificates; only the Bitwarden domain had an issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried restarting the Caddy service and reloading the configuration, but to no avail. Helplessly, I had to check Caddy's execution logs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The error message in the logs revealed the truth: &lt;strong>When Caddy tried to apply for a new HTTPS certificate, it needed to verify through the HTTP port (HTTP-01 challenge). However, this verification request was directly intercepted by Tencent Cloud, which returned a page with a non-registration prompt.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So, the core reason was found: &lt;strong>Tencent Cloud upgraded its firewall policy. Previously, for unregistered domains, only access to port 80 was intercepted. Now, it intercepts all ports for external services.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This policy directly caused Caddy's certificate renewal/application mechanism to fail completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-struggle-and-abandonment">3. Struggle and Abandonment&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="attempting-to-migrate-the-domain">Attempting to Migrate the Domain&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since it was a Tencent Cloud issue, I thought, could I migrate the domain resolution to Cloudflare and use Cloudflare's DNS service to bypass this restriction?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, when I tried to modify the domain's NS (Name Server) records in the Tencent Cloud console, I found that this option was locked! To modify it, I had to go through an independent and somewhat hidden &amp;quot;DNS Server Modification&amp;quot; entry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the migration, I found it was actually useless. The interception actually happened on the server rather than at the DNS resolution level (or perhaps there were interceptions on both sides).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-final-solution">4. Final Solution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the end, for stability and peace of mind, I chose to pay for a Bitwarden Premium subscription ($10 a year) and stopped tinkering. These domestic personal cloud servers feel less and less useful. If it weren't for the blog needing an ICP registration number which requires a domestic cloud server, I would definitely shut it down and switch to overseas cloud servers.&lt;/p></description><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/posts/">posts</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Rant/">Rant</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Tools/">Tools</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Notes/">Notes</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Cloud-Services/">Cloud Services</category><category domain="https://scottyeung.top/en/tags/Cloudflare/">Cloudflare</category></item></channel></rss>